SAILOR [OVER SPEAKER]: Pearl Harbor outer marker, 30 minutes.
- Hey, Case! What's happening? - Tackman, how you doing?
Where's your whites? The prez is coming.
He won't miss me.
What's this? You're in the Navy, you've got to look good. There we go.
- Cue Ball! - Where's your whites?
- Poor boy doesn't have a dress uniform. - I've got the dress, I forgot the pumps.
Tell him not to worry. Everything here is handled.
Oh, my God.
No, no. No, no, no, that's okay. We'll take care of it.
Well, it's gonna be a zoo.
- Chief Ryback, captain. - Yeah, send him in.
Get in your dress uniform.
You know how I feel about ceremonies. I thought this time...
If I had your ribbons, I'd wear them to bed.
Yes, sir.
Get in your whites. I'll introduce you to the president.
RYBACK: I appreciate that, but... - That's not a good idea.
For once, Commander Krill and I are in total agreement.
I have 50 gallons of bouillabaisse I need to prepare by tomorrow.
- My birthday? - I could do the cheeseburger routine.
It's not for me, it's the crew. They really love that stuff. So we'll do that.
Just don't show your face until after the ceremony.
Yes, sir.
You're a sorry-looking sailor.
That I am, sir. Thank you, sir.
Sir...
why do you tolerate that clown?
I know he's a good cook...
He's more than a good cook. You have no idea. Now let him be, XO.
Yes, sir.
NEWSCASTER: Fifty years ago today...
the infamous Japanese attack destroyed the Pacific fleet...
here in Pearl Harbor.
Today, in honor of those who lost their lives, the USS Missouri returns.
Built to avenge Pearl Harbor, she did.
Days after we dropped the bomb on Hiroshima...
the Japanese surrendered on the Missouri's deck...
ending World War ll.
The Missouri fired the first shots of the Gulf War.
Her powerful 1 6-inch guns destroyed Iraqi bunkers.
Her Tomahawk missiles rocketed deep into the heart of Baghdad.
The fastest and most powerful dreadnought ever to sail the seas....
Where's your tattoo?
Where I got it, you don't want to see.
NEWSCASTER: The last battleship left in the world, BB 63 will be decommissioned.
President Bush is paying final tribute to the ship...
and her great history.
Did you hear the joke when Andre and Beaudreau went hunting on the bayou?
"Where're the guns, Druillet?"
That's about right.
BUSH: In the end this unity of purpose....
These ceremonies not only remember war, they celebrate peace.
NEWSCASTER: The president ordered the removal of all Tomahawk cruise missiles...
from U.S. surface ships.
Tomorrow the ship embarks for San Francisco for her final voyage.
Her weaponry will be removed, dismantled, and never fired again.
The Missouri will then take her place in naval history.
We will gain the inevitable triumph, so help us God.
Look at the money spent on this photo opportunity.
Ready to get under way, sir.
Very well, let's single up.
Aye, sir. Single up all lines.
- Captain, you have clear water to port. - Very well.
No, no, no.
Krill ain't running this ship.
The old man has to okay all helicopter landings.
How's the captain going to authorize a surprise party for himself?
JOHNSON: We already stowed all the gear.
- What's on this helicopter? - This little sweetheart.
- Damn. She's in the...? - Yeah, she's in the cake.
That is Miss July '89. Jordan Tate.
- We'll be ready for her. - Good. Go ahead and keep that.
Lieutenant, we don't have time to talk about this now.
BALLARD: No time for the security of nuclear weapons?
Maybe I'm not being clear.
Any watches not crucial shall be secured during the party...
including the Marine roving patrol.
We're operating on a skeleton crew.
This is a direct order.
The log will show I consider this unsafe, and obeyed under protest.
Fine.
- You missed a spot. - Aye, sir.
Hey, Cue Ball.
- Cue Ball in the house. - What's up?
Show me a move!
Turn up the tunes! Turn up the tunes!
Show them some moves, Cue Ball. Show them the moves.
Go, Cue Ball! Go, Cue Ball, go!
That was cute.
Petty Officer Ryback?
- Ensign Taylor. - Sir.
You don't have to "sir" me. We're casual in the galley.
I'd watch it. We still have a week together.
I guess I won't get to see you go through puberty.
What do you want?
I have orders from the XO on the captain's birthday.
We're having dinner flown in from Hawaii.
This galley will be cleared by 1700.
You and your crew are to assemble at the mess deck prior to the helo's arrival.
Negative.
Excuse me?
Only I cook for the captain. You don't like that, talk to him.
I don't believe you get it.
See, this is a surprise party.
No one is going to talk to the captain about this.
You know something?
He don't like surprises. Neither do I.
Then I guess we'll just see what we'll see. Won't we?
There go that little redhead, boss.
"I guess we'll just see what we'll see. Won't we?"
Hey, Ryback, man. Krill's going to skin you alive.
Why is it that I'm starting to shake so bad...
and there's this deep fear in me...
thinking about Mr. Krill and the horrible things he'll do to me?
Commander Krill.
Send him in.
You wanted to see me, captain?
Commander Krill...
how'd you expect to land a helicopter without my authorization?
- It was a mistake to think... - It was a mistake to try.
Your actions are grossly insubordinate.
I want an explanation. Now.
Admiral Bates wanted to thank you for how smoothly things went.
He has a surprise for your birthday.
He's flying in from Hawaii.
Bates, I see. If the admiral wants a party, I guess we'll have one.
Let's keep it simple. Off-duty personnel can attend...
but watches are by the book.
Yes, sir.
Captain...
since he wants this to be a surprise...
if you could stay here till we come for you....
- I'll be engrossed in a novel. - Very good, sir.
RAMIREZ: How's that bouillabaisse? Heads up!
We'll carry it in. This needs some more.
Excuse me.
If I'm not mistaken...
every one of you has orders to report to the mess deck...
for the party.
You stand fast.
Everyone else go! Now.
RAMIREZ: See you at the party, Casey.
KRILL: You know...
this does look delicious.
It smells like a lard omelet.
I put up with your shit...
because the captain likes your cooking.
But this time he won't be here to save you.
Is that right?
Little flavor.
You like that?
- Fucking crazy? - That's striking an officer!
That's not striking an officer!
That's striking an officer!
- Okay! All right! TAYLOR: Cuff him and throw him in the brig!
- Throw him in the brig! - You need the old man's signature.
Good point.
Secure him in the meat locker.
Now! Right now.
MARINE: Let's go.
Now I know why you're a cook. You hit like a faggot.
Steel.
Private Nash...
- ...you came on board in Hawaii? - Yes, sir.
Then you don't know about Ryback.
He is an extreme psychopath.
He hates officers. He hates America.
This is the captain's birthday. I don't want him ruining it.
No one speaks to him or lets him out.
If he tries to escape, shoot him right here.
I'm counting on you.
Yes, sir.
Let's go.
Another cold day in hell.
It speaks well for the Navy that we can entertain a ship at sea.
It's so human.
And I love that. Don't you?
I just hope I don't throw up.
You'll be fine.
I love it. I love it!
[CHEERING]
Goddamn!
Watch your step there.
- Welcome to the USS Missouri. - Thanks.
You okay?
Fantastic!
We're quite excited. We're looking forward to a great time.
God, I love this business!
TACKMAN: My future wife.
She's landed.
The Bunny's landed. See you.
RYBACK: Private!
Doesn't it seem strange that Krill put me in here?
I ain't listening to you.
SAILOR 1: Welcome aboard. - Okay.
SAILOR 2: Guys, make a hole. - Okay.
Don't let them bother you. Been at sea too long. You okay?
I still feel really queasy.
We'll go to the wardroom, where you can change.
DAUMER: Let the lady through!
KRILL: Be careful with the cake. Make sure the wires are covered.
That's the way it goes.
- Are you lost? - No, no. Where do you want us?
- Is the band Set up? - Ready to go.
You're over here.
Starboard side, right now.
You'll knock the captain off his feet. You're beautiful.
- For motion sickness. Take two. - This will save me.
- What happened to your face? - Cut myself shaving.
The cake's almost ready.
We have a room for you to change. You'll be safe from my men.
- I'm gonna put on my party dress. - All right.
See you later. Let's go, get in line!
Hey.
Don't worry. You can play this with your eyes shut.
Private!
Let me out!
You follow Krill's orders, you'll go to the brig! Use your head!
Go get my pies out of the oven!
I must be nuts.
Very sick. Very sick.
We want to give you a great big welcome...
to the big, big, beautiful Missouri lounge...
out here in the middle of the big beautiful Pacific Ocean.
I'm Bad Billy.
And these are the fabulous Bail Jumpers!
I have orders not to talk to you. Understand? Orders.
RYBACK: You could be held accountable...
keeping me in here like this.
You have to think about that.
Private?
He didn't say you can't talk to the captain.
Go ask him if he wants me in here.
You little E-1 prick.
Lieutenant, this is absolutely beautiful.
[SINGING]
Old man says keep her level.
How about an hors d'oeuvre?
What have we here?
All right. There's the Twinkies. Where's Miss July?
And there she is.
Miss July 1 989.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute. No, no!
That's not Miss July.
My God, look at him.
STRANNIX: Commander Krill.
Welcome to the revolution.
This party will make history. No wonder he wanted everyone here.
Maybe Krill isn't such an asshole after all.
That's great. Go get the old man. He's been waiting on you now.
All right.
Miss July!
DAUMER: Let's go see the old man.
We're going to surprise the captain now.
- Have a good party! DAUMER: Come on, dear.
Hey, where's the chief?
In the meat locker until after the party.
It's only like 40 degrees in there.
He'll be fine. He's got a guard.
Yeah?
Krill's a maniac. Tell the captain he spit in my soup.
NASH: You got a fire in here.
Get my pies out of the oven!
Jeez.
KRILL: Feels good walking around in these pantyhose.
It's okay. I'm here to escort the captain to the party.
Aye, commander.
- Commander Krill. - Send him in.
Krill?
I'm your date tonight, captain.
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
Who is the highest-ranking officer here?
Who is the highest-ranking officer in this room?
All right, sir. Stand up.
Stand up and be recognized.
Part the waves there. Get out of the man's way.
Put a light on the man.
Now, you, sir, are the highest-ranking officer in this room?
Yes. Operations officer. Third in command.
It's a pleasure to meet you, Commander Green.
Get down!
What's going on?
The party's just beginning.
Captain!
KRILL: Good shot.
Get down! Hands up!
Heads down!
What are you looking at? On the floor!
Put your head down.
- You gonna be good now, boy? - Yes, sir.
What is this, a joke?
No joke!
I hear gunfire. What's going on?
It's done.
Four minutes ahead of schedule. Damn, I'm good.
Come on!
Come on! Move it!
Let's go.
Mother Goose, the quails are in the nest.
NASH: It's just the music.
You got shit for brains. That's gunfire. Call the bridge.
I don't know who you're talking to. No one's listening to you.
I ain't asking you to listen to me.
Call the captain. Listen to him.
Oh, Ryback.
Seal it!
Let's move it! Move your feet! Let's go!
- Let's go! Move! Move! - Move your feet!
SHADOW: Eyes on the man in front of you!
Goddamn it, that's the last time I'll tell you!
Shit!
Let this be a learning experience.
If you resist, we will kill you and the man next to you.
Now move out of here in an orderly fashion.
Now!
What the hell?
COMMANDO: Turn around. Hands on your head.
KRILL: Where is it? Where is it?
Here it is. Here it is.
Listen to the shit I've had to put up with.
"Commander Krill has become increasingly hostile to the crew...
possibly due to anger over reviews of his performance.
I recommend psychological evaluation before his next assignment."
Do I look like I need a psychological evaluation?
Not at all.
I got to change.
COMMANDO 1: Behind your head.
COMMANDO 2: On your toes!
Up against the wall.
CREWMAN: XO on the bridge.
KRILL: Listen up.
Hands on your head and move to the counter, right now.
Your destination is the fo'c's'le. Cooperate and you won't be harmed.
Change of watch.
You've done a good job, but you're relieved of duty.
Get your hand off that console.
You're a cheeky bastard. Move out!
My God! Bunch of wussies.
The disk, Mr. Pitt.
Guard it with your life.
Of course.
Bring up the layout, if you will.
- We've overridden their systems. - We control crypto, CIC...
engine rooms, boiler rooms, bridge and all open decks.
We've welded shut the hatches.
A few loose sailors may be berthing...
or they're caught in nonessential areas and can go nowhere.
- The rest are in the fo'c's'le. STRANNIX: Excellent. Excellent.
Reactivate the weapons systems, Mr. Pitt.
Mr. Daumer...
you may deploy the welding crews and chop up broadway.
Commander Krill, you're hereby promoted to captain.
Congratulations. The ship is yours.
The ship is mine.
Thank you, Billy. All right!
- Can we get something to eat in here?! COMMANDO: Yes, sir.
Get some food!
Krill warned me you were tricky.
I'm not tricky, I'm just freezing. Something's going on here.
Call the bridge. No one will yell at you.
You're just doing your job. Check right away.
All right. All right, I'll check in.
That's all.
Do that. And be careful.
STRANNIX: 'Tis a rare thing.
This is good. It'll work.
Got a call from Private Nash on guard duty in the kitchen.
- Pitt, pull it up. - Shit, shit, shit.
That's an unsecured area. They can access the whole ship.
Ryback.
Ryback?
Ryback. A cook. A pain-in-the-ass cook.
Give me that.
- Private Nash. - Yes, sir.
KRILL: I'm glad you checked in. I've been with the captain.
Keep Ryback under control and don't open the door.
- Tell him you're sending relief. - What?
Tell him you are sending somebody to relieve him.
Stand your station fast. I'm sending someone to relieve you.
Is everything all right? We heard what sounded like gunshots.
Gunshots? Oh, that.
Those are party poppers. Firecrackers.
Part of the party.
Stand firm until you're relieved.
- Yes, sir. - Over and out.
STRANNIX: Anything else you didn't tell us?
Any further memory lapses or oversights, perhaps?
No other memory lapses or oversights, perhaps.
There's two men. One's locked up. I'll take care of it.
No, no, no.
We'll handle it. Secure the galley. Send Cates and Ziggs.
KRILL: This Marine's armed.
We should send more. I'll go.
Don't worry. They're professionals.
They can handle 20 Marines...
and 1 00 cooks.
You're wrong, Ryback. You're wrong.
- They were party poppers. - You got shit for brains.
I know they brainwashed you, but you have to question authority.
Trust me, boy.
That's gunfire. Get me out of here and I'll take care of it.
I'll be relieved in a few minutes, so just shut up and sit tight.
RYBACK: Something's going on. Use your head this time.
Do what you got to do. Get me out.
Or when I'm out, I'll shoot you myself.
[METAL CLANGS]
Commander Krill?
Is that you?
Hey....
Get your hands on your head. Turn around.
Get down on your knees.
Cross your ankles.
Where's the cook?
In the reefer.
Which one?
COMMANDO: Son of a bitch!
COMMANDO: Cates. Hey, Cates.
[PILOT SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY OVER RADIO]
- Hey, Pitt. PITT: Yeah.
We've got an F-1 8.
Daumer, they're sending an F-1 8 to look for the chopper.
PILOT: Heading 31 5 miles, speed 430, approximately 8000.
Two-zero-seven, 61 miles now.
Bearing 1 80.
Heading 330.
Four-thirty. Five thousand now, into descent.
We're going down now.
Looks like one helo on deck.
Going in for a closer look.
Thirty-one to Missouri, over.
Goodbye!
PILOT: Are you tracking me?
PITT: Negative.
PILOT: He's locked me up! Mayday.
Welcome to the revolution.
- Better call the office. - Good idea.
You're in deep kimchi, buddy.
Better have it all in one sock for this one.
Claims he was a company man who worked for you.
BREAKER: What's his name?
William Strannix.
Jesus Christ!
Not good.
BATES: Mr. Breaker...
you better be candid with us here tonight.
We need answers, and we need them now.
STRANNIX [OVER SPEAKER]: Gentlemen, if any ships or aircraft...
approach within 1 00 miles...
we will kill the crew and retaliate with everything in the ship's arsenal.
Bill, this is Tom. What's going on?
STRANNIX: Hi, Tom.
I have 32 Tomahawks under my thumb...
and all you can do is alert the media.
You don't have the launch codes.
Let me guess.
"5-6-6-0-4-9-9-7-8-0?"
This is insane.
STRANNIX: Be careful with that word, Tom.
Mr. Strannix, this is Admiral Bates speaking.
Would you please tell us why the hell you're doing this.
STRANNIX: Hi, admiral.
Six months ago, Tom Breaker canceled Operation Cleopatra.
Shortly thereafter, two young men from Langley tried to cancel me.
You received each man's right forefinger in the mail, didn't you, Tom?
Tom?
Yes, I did.
Did you expect us to wait for you to try again?
BREAKER: Look, Bill...
I know things are a little...
- ...chaotic for you right now. STRANNIX: Chaotic!
Wake up, Tom!
[TAPPING]
You and I know that chaos and bedlam are consuming the entire world.
UV rays are only the beginning. We have an inch of topsoil left.
Topsoil?
STRANNIX: Sexually transmitted diseases, depletion of the gene pool.
It adds up to oblivion.
Governments will fall. Anarchies will reign.
- It's a brave new world. BREAKER: Bill?
What are you planning to do?
STRANNIX: Do you realize that whatever I do is inevitable? Can we agree on that?
Not necessarily.
There you go.
You can't argue with me or negotiate or attempt a ploy.
You have to reconsider your philosophy.
All right, I'm sorry. Whatever you decide to do is inevitable.
STRANNIX: Look at my life.
The life you tried to take. There was Annapolis, Vietnam, so on.
I missed the '60s, and I believe if I had been there...
to contribute, everything would've worked out fine.
Bill, if this is about reliving the '60s, you can forget it.
The movement is dead.
Hence the name.
"Movement." It moves a certain distance, then it stops.
Revolution gets its name by always coming back around in your face.
You tried to kill me, you son of a bitch.
So welcome to the revolution.
There's more to follow. I'll stay in touch.
He's flipped.
He's completely flipped.
I want an inventory of everything on that ship.
Aye-aye, sir.
General, here's what we know.
The threat is verifiable. It is real. I repeat, it is real.
Shit! You son of a bitch.
Think they believe you?
They believe I'm crazy, paranoid or something.
I have a harpoon locked on.
Fire when ready.
Pipe down, men! Pipe down.
Missile away.
Oh, boy.
Oh, boy, oh, boy.
Bang! You're dead.
- He's taken out satellite relay. - What doesn't he want us to see?
He wants to blind us.
It's illogical. We can follow his movement from Pearl.
You can vector an AWACS.
- Or send E-2C from Nimitz. - Make it happen.
Wake up the president.
FOREMAN: Bring it in.
Keep it coming in.
Cut it fast. Time is money on this deal.
KRILL: This better be a competent crew. FOREMAN: Get your ass up there!
Watch your heads.
KRILL: Glad I sent you the blueprints.
I have four sections this way, seven sections this way.
I'll have it cut and up in an hour.
FOREMAN: Time is money on this job!
Time is money.
This will cut them to the bone. Right to the bone.
Whoa.
[CLANGING]
What's that noise?
That's my beloved crew.
CHIEF: Keep trying. Keep pounding. Someone will hear us.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYS ON RADIO]
RYBACK: Whoa!
Shut the music off.
What the hell is going on?
What happened to them?
- Who are you and what are you doing here? - My name is Jordan Tate.
I'm Miss July '89.
I was hired to jump out of the cake...
but I got airsick on the way here and so...
this guy gave me these pills.
- I guess I fell asleep. - What kind of bullshit is this?
I am an actress, okay?
I did a Hunter episode and a Wet 'n Wild video.
My agent said I was going to jump out of the cake.
How many on the chopper?
I don't know.
It was full. There was a band and caterers.
Where's the crew?
I don't know. I didn't see anything.
You didn't see or hear anything and don't remember anything?
I've done stupid things in my life...
but believe me, I don't know anything.
All right, I believe you.
So who are you? Are you a special forces guy or something?
I'm just a cook.
A cook?
Just a lowly, lowly cook.
Oh, my God, we're gonna die.
AIDE: The ship contains 40,000 rounds of 20 mm CWIZ.
Over 1 000 1 6-inch projectiles.
We believe there's 1 5 harpoon cruise missiles still aboard...
and 32 Tomahawks.
What kind of Tomahawks?
It's all right. It's okay.
Eight of them are specials.
Nuclear-tipped. 220 kilotons each.
Mr. Breaker, would you explain how this nut could hold a top position...
in an intelligence agency?
Would you answer that?
High-level covert operatives like Strannix are under great stress.
They're creative thinkers who, by their very nature...
Tom trains everyone in the CIA who's crazy.
All we want to know is how he got our battleship.
That's his specialty.
North Korea was refitting a sub to fire antiship missiles...
so we sent Strannix in.
You've been financing this maniac's private army?
It didn't occur to you it might become a problem?
Once we realized we had lost positive control...
under Executive Order 1 36, we tried to neutralize him. We missed.
TRENTON: Excuse me.
This North Korean sub....
How do you know he sunk it?
Oh, we're positive he sunk it.
Positive.
PITT [OVER RADIO]: Roadrunner to Tweety Bird. Do you read me? Come in.
DAMIANI: Tweety Bird to Roadrunner. We're nearby.
- How's it going? PITT: Sub's up.
- It's all rock 'n' roll to me. DAMIANI: Any sign of Wile E. Coyote?
No. Meet at the birdcage. Roadrunner out.
- You're the Roadrunner? - Yeah.
Never been caught.
- Problem. Cates and Ziggs are missing. - Missing?
COMMANDO: I've been radioing them for five minutes. No response.
- The last location? COMMANDO: The galley.
I told you to send more men. I told you.
JORDAN: Please don't leave me here alone.
Believe me, this is the safest place you can be. Understand?
No!
Let me out of here!
[BANGING ON LOCKER]
Let me out!
Do you understand what'll happen if anybody hears you?
They'll try to kill us.
Now be quiet.
[BANGING ON LOCKER]
I hate being alone.
Do you hate being dead?
Check it out.
- Clear! - Clear!
Put those on.
Okay, you're coming with me, you got to be invisible.
If you walk by a hatch and see the enemy, you become the hatch.
I'm giving you this rifle with a selector switch on it.
One is fully automatic, one is semiautomatic.
The definition of semiautomatic is, when you depress the trigger...
one round will go off.
That's what I want to give you. Spend one round at a time. Okay?
Turn on the lights.
Check the breaker box. It's happened before.
Man who did this is a professional.
- Who is he and why is he on my ship? KRILL: Your ship?
You wouldn't be on this battleship if not for me.
He's a cook, plain and simple.
- This is not the work of a cook. - He came with the captain.
I know his routine front and back. He's good with cooking knives.
Shit! Cooking knives!
He got lucky.
In my professional opinion, he is a military reject...
in command of a galley.
[BEEPING]
KRILL: Get down!
- What was that? - A bomb, jackass.
He used the microwave as a detonator.
Secure everything between here and the CIC.
You see anything, radio at once for backup. Understand?
Put these fires out!
I'd like to see the personnel file on this plain-and-simple cook.
- Yes, sir. - Put out these goddamn fires!
SEAL Team 5 will launch from Nimitz aboard a CH-53 Echo...
with an Apache gunship in support.
At the objective area, the Apache will take out the ship's radar...
and her electronic warfare systems.
Then SEAL Team 5 will board and retake the vessel.
And the odds of success?
If it's a lunatic who only partly controls the ship...
the odds are good.
But if he's ready for us...
if he's prepared to repel boarders...
the odds are not good.
Bear in mind, the operators from SEAL Team 5 are the best there are.
BATES: This is our only hope of saving the crew and retaking the ship intact.
Let me make one thing absolutely clear:
If the SEAL team fails...
we will have no alternative but to launch an air strike...
and destroy the Missouri.
You know what that means.
We'll get her back for you.
Make it happen. Make it happen.
DAUMER: Twenty-two, 1 2, perfect.
It's 44 feet from the weather deck to the missile canisters.
It'll take a half hour to assemble that section of the crane.
Ryback's file wasn't in personnel. It was in the captain's private cabinet.
Ryback is an ex-SEAL.
The goddamn cook's a SEAL?
Shut up and listen. "Expert in martial arts...
explosives, weapons, tactics.
Silver Star. Navy Cross. Purple Heart with cluster.
Security revoked after Panama." So he could only rate as a yeoman...
or a cook. How little did I know.
We lost two men in the engine room.
You were told to review every crew member's file.
I know, but I didn't have access to the captain's files!
- I'll get this fucker myself. STRANNIX: Oh, no, calm down.
- Want to get killed? - Are you an idiot?
- You're calling me an idiot? - Yeah, I am.
Calm down. Get me three roving patrols. Keep him below the weather deck.
- Move out! - Stay on schedule!
To the bridge!
JORDAN: I'm the girl. Why do I have to carry everything?
- I support women's lib, don't you? - When it works in my favor.
STRANNIX [OVER RADIO]: Hear this, all personnel.
- Move ahead. - Beware of booby traps.
Do not pursue hostile parties into areas of the ship we do not control.
Report to Daumer individually at five-minute intervals and switch...
to the alternate frequency.
Now.
Goddamn SEAL.
I'll carry everything...
if you kill whoever we run into.
I have a rule about killing people.
Actually, I have two rules. One:
I don't date musicians. And two: I don't kill people.
I'm thrilled to death to hear that.
But it leaves a lot of open territory. Get up the ladder.
- Let's go. - God!
I think you've got the wrong partner.
Now wait here.
Sit down there.
I'll be back in a minute.
JORDAN: What's that?
What is that?
This is a SEAL magnaphone.
It's an MX 20-20. It's a secure satellite uplink.
Like a car phone.
Yeah. Something like that.
Excuse me, this is hot.
You know Casey Ryback?
Chief Ryback?
He's top hand in the Teams. Wish we had him here.
He reached us on a SEAL magnaphone. He's on the Missouri.
What?
Listen. Everyone listen up.
RADIOMAN [OVER SPEAKER]: Affirmative. Roger that.
Can you estimate the size of the force?
- I'd say about 30. - Affirmative.
We'll connect you to Captain Garza.
Stand by.
What if he's working for them?
Hey, I'll guarantee Ryback. He's a good guy.
TRENTON: Wait a minute.
We won't take the chance. Don't tell him about our response.
- Chief Ryback, Captain Garza. RYBACK: Glad you're there.
What we want you to do is just feed us on-site intel.
This man may be crazy, but he's a professional.
They're manufacturing a railing system to offload the Tomahawks.
Believe it or not, the XO's with them.
Commander Krill's involved?
Admiral...
that means they control the ship.
Holy God.
Chief Ryback, this is Admiral Bates speaking.
Sir.
Coordinate your efforts with us. I want you to keep cool...
and wait for the strike team. Do you understand?
I'd better get off before they pick up the signal.
BATES: Call us in half an hour. - Roger that.
You're not a cook.
Yeah, well...
I also cook.
Get your stuff.
He had an extremely distinguished career until Panama...
when most of his team was killed due to poor intelligence.
GARZA: Ryback's a warrior. The best there is.
When he got back from Panama, he punched his officer in charge.
Adams took him on as a cook so he could finish his 20.
TRENTON: Hold it. Just hold it.
What if this toad, Zwieback, or whatever his name is, is right...
and the missiles are offloaded before the SEAL team gets there?
There is no way for Mr. Strannix to get past us.
We have AWAC surveillance and SOSUS in Honolulu...
tracking every ship and sub at sea.
They leave the Missouri, they're ours.
How do we know that Honolulu isn't his next target?
Tell me that.
KRILL: Take a look at this.
STRANNIX: Know what all those lights are for?
KRILL: I've been trained.
FOREMAN: Come on! All right. All right.
- You can fly that helicopter? - Yeah.
JORDAN: Then we can get out of here, right? RYBACK: No.
Here's the MP5K.
When the dot's on target, what you see is what you get.
- I told you I don't like guns. - I know. Neither do I.
Now get back under there.
These things are going to sell like hot cakes!
Absolutely.
What are you gonna do with $200 million in the bank?
Buy the presidency.
COMMANDO: Someone's moving. Right there!
KRILL: He's on the flight deck! Go! Go!
COMMANDO: Come on out of there!
[JORDAN YELLS]
JORDAN: Where are you taking me? I don't know anything! I don't know!
Let go of me! Leave me alone!
Get your hands off of me!
Now! God, leave me alone!
RYBACK: Move!
COMMANDO: There he is!
Move!
Stand fast! Do not pursue that man!
- Secure missile battery three, now! - Man that hatch!
This guy's a pain in the ass!
DAUMER: We got to do something about him.
I know what to do.
I do.
This insanity is so logical.
There's a sprinkler system where they're being held.
Mr. Pitt?
The fo'c's'le.
Hit a button, it starts to flood.
In a short time, they'll all drown.
Ryback'll kill himself trying to save them.
Mr. Pitt.
[ALL YELLING]
You're a maniac.
Drowning your own crew.
They never liked me anyway.
DAUMER: Bet they fucking love you now.
You see this? These are cut everywhere.
What is that?
They're for a railing system to offload the missiles onto a ship or sub...
they're gonna rendezvous with.
[TAPPING]
What's that?
RYBACK: Morse code.
What are they saying?
"Get me the fuck out of here."
- What's that? - Get away from the hatch!
Now what?
GRANGER: Ryback?
Johnson, guard the door. Shoot anyone who comes through.
You okay?
Yeah. Are you okay?
Yeah.
- Is this all of you? - What you see.
Six of us got trapped. What's going on?
We got a problem. Who's this?
Calaway, Gunner's mate, 2nd class, '44, '46.
This is Jordan. She's a casualty of the situation I'll brief you on.
- Hi. - Nice to see you. You too, Case.
Granger, you take this.
- Get your tools. We've got work to do. - Right.
RYBACK: We're jumping into a shit storm here.
PITT: Whoa!
Must've been a power surge.
Yeah.
That's the last one.
This should disable their weapons systems within a half an hour.
Mr. Ryback, may I have your attention, please?
This is Captain Krill speaking.
I'd like you to look at the monitors...
where you are at this point in time.
Are you watching?
I prepared a special show for you.
Here it goes.
I want you to know there are no hard feelings.
I have no grudge against you...
or the rest of the crew.
You did your best.
Discipline is right out the window here.
FLICKER: Granger, turn it off.
We got to save them.
They'll have a trap.
But they're expecting me, not all of us.
All of what? I do laundry.
I ironed during the Gulf War. I ain't cut out for this.
You're in the Navy, remember?
"It's not a job, it's an adventure."
To hell with that. I'm on the college program.
- I'm with you, Case. - Let's do it.
We're out of here.
All right, I'll stay and watch Miss July.
- Get the lights out in broadway. - I'm going.
Okay, but the emergency lights will kick on soon.
All right, what the hell. How does this work?
Go!
Take cover! Take cover! Come on, guys!
RYBACK: Take cover! Get down!
Turn it!
Turn the water off!
CHIEF: They're gonna get us out of here!
They're gonna get us out!
Pull him out of there! Pull him out of there!
Help him, Tack! Help him!
Come on, buddy!
Breathe!
JORDAN: Listen to him!
TACKMAN: Hang in there!
Shit!
KRILL: We'll be offoading in an hour.
COMMANDO [OVER RADIO]: Listen, he freed a few men, and I think...
they went into the fo'c's'le, but we got them pinned down.
Kill them if you can't contain them.
It worked. They're trapped.
- Good. FOREMAN: Drop the anchor!
This is where it's going to happen.
[MAGNAPHONE BEEPING]
JORDAN [OVER SPEAKER]: Hello?
- Who in the hell is this? JORDAN: Who in the hell is this?
This is Admiral Bates. I'm trying to get ahold of Ryback.
JORDAN: He's in a gunfight. I'll have to take a message.
What's going on there?
Hold on. Here.
Yes, sir.
Chief Ryback, this is Admiral Bates.
I see that you completely disobeyed my orders. Correct?
RYBACK: Sorry. You can court-martial me if I live.
I see.
Listen to me carefully.
SEAL Team 5 is en route. You understand?
Yes, sir.
Nimitz air group is our backup. Understand?
Now, since your ass is on the line, I authorize you...
to do whatever you can to aid the arrival of the SEALs.
Because if I goddamn can't control you...
- ...I might as well support you. Correct? RYBACK: That's affirmative, sir.
You....
You have some good luck there, sailor. I'm out.
They got a lot of trouble on that ship.
RYBACK: Here I go.
I'm not staying here.
- Where are you going? - What did you say to her?
RYBACK: What are you doing? - The safest place is behind you.
Hug the wall. Get out of the middle!
TACKMAN: Miss July, come back here!
Casey!
PILOT [OVER RADIO]: TAG leader, this is Cobra escort. We have you in our sights.
You should see us on your portside now.
Francois, put the money in the Zurich bank now, or nothing will happen.
Fuck you, Strannix!
Sell what we got in MacGregor Aircraft.
It'll go to shit when they find out about this.
Two choppers trying to sneak in under our radar.
Strike team.
We drive a hard bargain for hard value.
You give me any more trouble, I'll call Mohammed. Understand?
PITT: Strike team is in range and locked on.
Kill them.
Not you, Francois. I'll put my accountant on the line...
with my account number. Talk to that frog.
PITT: Strannix?
Something's wrong.
We've got a big problem here. Switch to auxiliary!
Nothing.
Shit, I lost the phalanx. We're sitting ducks.
STRANNIX: Get me secure to the sub.
Sub's up.
Coyote, this is Roadrunner. Come in.
[HELICOPTER APPROACHES]
Here come the good guys.
One minute!
The fantail's fouled up! We're going in on the bow.
What the hell was that?!
AIDE: It's confirmed. We lost them all.
BATES: We have no choice now...
but full air assault from the Nimitz.
Mr. Trenton, would you please?
We need more hands on deck to help tie this sub up.
Start offloading.
The crane isn't finished. We got another problem below decks.
Pull four men off the welding crew to help tie up the sub.
- Go. - Yes, sir.
My goodness!
Daumer, Daumer, Daumer. Why didn't you hire this person?
Whatever his price would've been, it would've been worth it.
COMMANDO: Bring it up!
Okay, okay. Ease it over. Ease it over now.
COMMANDO 1: Number seven. Number seven. Get number seven now.
COMMANDO 2: Easy!
DAUMER: There's someone in the water!
Behind you!
- I saw someone in the water! - Hey! Hey!
CREWMAN: Hook him!
Hook that son of a bitch!
Check for a bomb!
Who saw him? Come on!
You're incredible, Ryback.
It's a shame you're not cooking for us.
[GUNSHOTS]
Next thing I know...
you'll be dating musicians.
[CREWMAN 1 SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
CREWMAN 2: What the hell you doing over there?
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Where's Daumer?
Probably dead.
The bowplane is jammed.
We can't submerge.
I'll handle it. It'll be operational under way.
You fix it, I'll make you an admiral.
Consider it done. Where are you going?
- Make Honolulu glow in the dark. - Outstanding.
I'll meet you 1 5 miles due south in the captain's launch.
Rally your men here in zero one.
I need an acetylene torch, an arc welder and a crowbar, now!
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
- What'd he say? - He can't fix it.
I'll fix it! Go! Now!
Why can't you speak English?
Hang in there, Casey.
Talk to me.
There's nothing to say.
Whatever they did...
they're smarter than I am.
Everything's dead.
It's hopeless.
Nothing is hopeless. Take heart.
Give me time, I'll figure it out.
I like your attitude. Excellent.
RAMIREZ: It's clear. Hey, Case.
What the hell?
KRILL: I'll put it to you in plain English. It is so simple.
Hammer that rod into place.
Weld it over the bowplane. Without it, we can't survive.
Make him understand. Now!
Where's Johnson?
- He's gone. - We can't let them get away with this!
What about those 5-inch guns?
No good. We offloaded all the armor-piercing rounds. We got starbursts.
Nothing that will penetrate.
Calaway.
- Gunner's mate. - Yeah, chief.
See those?
We still got shells for those.
I did it.
It's charging. In a few minutes we'll have enough power to fire.
Well done.
CALAWAY: Let's go!
RYBACK: Get on those last three bags!
CALAWAY: Out of line.
- Another one. RYBACK: Watch my hand signals!
CALAWAY: Stand clear!
Easy, guys, easy. Just glide it through.
What's the sub's course and speed?
Course 1 72. Speed six knots.
Get down the 5-inch guns!
JORDAN: What do you want me to do? RYBACK: See those black switches?
- Click them on, one by one. - If the sub blows, won't the nukes go?
No. They won't detonate.
They'll sink with the sub.
Lower the cradle.
Cradle lowered.
- Ram the projectile. CALAWAY: Easy.
Ram the powder easy.
CALAWAY: Real easy.
Starbursts are ready.
Fire the starburst!
All right.
You, secure this room. Get back to work, jack-off!
DAMIANI: They're firing at us!
They're just desperate.
Those are starbursts. They don't have shells to hurt us.
Two-zero-four degrees, Calaway.
Elevate the barrel.
Zero-two-eight degrees.
Fire in the hole.
KRILL: He's doing it! We're out of time!
They're reloading right now.
Granger, Tackman! Reload!
Lowering cradle.
Scoot over!
Goddamn it!
Close the breech.
Lower it. Lower the bowplane!
Pull! It's working! It's working! Come on, let's go.
Two-four-one degrees.
CALAWAY: Two-four-one degrees back.
Dive!
It's working!
RYBACK: Two-zero-four degrees. CALAWAY: Two-zero-four degrees.
This is it.
Ryback is gone.
Let me look.
Fire in the hole!
- Direct hit! - We hit it!
Strannix, what the hell is going on?
STRANNIX: Daffy Duck. Porky Pig.
Little red fucker with the mustache. The big chicken.
SHADOW: Strannix!
All of my life...
Saturday morning cartoons.
The best.
Shit.
For example...
remember those two little shrimp coming in, riding seahorses...
little chaps, little pistols?
Shooting back over their shoulders.
Rescue that lobster from the...
Swedish cook.
Funniest thing I ever saw!
- Splendid work, by the way. - Strannix!
Splendid work!
My, my, my...
how hell doth quicken the spirit.
- Tomahawks! - They're up and ready.
Where?
- Fire control. - Of course! The fire control.
Chips and dips on the weather deck.
Don't be late! Motor launch is waiting! All hands!
Clear out of here!
Let's go.
Strannix!
Four minutes.
- Four minutes. PITT: Meet us at the motor launch.
Four little minutes.
Home run.
JORDAN: Yeah!
CALAWAY: We did it!
This little piggy went to market.
This little piggy stayed home.
And this little piggy....
Oh, mama. Oh, mama.
All the way home!
[STRANNIX HUMMING "STAR-SPANGLED BANNER"]
[STRANNIX HUMMING "STAR-SPANGLES BANNER"]
Happy trails.
In the captain's launch, there's the MX 20-20, the SEAL magnaphone.
- Bring it here. Take her with you. - The what?
The car phone.
AIDE: Admiral? BATES: Yes, sir.
AIDE: The Nimitz is tracking two Tomahawks launched from the ship.
- Where are they headed? AIDE: Honolulu.
Oh, God.
- What's the flight time? - Twenty-four minutes, sir.
- Can we destroy them in the air? - Destruct codes are on the Missouri.
Scramble Navy and Air Force fighters from Pearl.
What are the consequences of missiles dropping on Honolulu?
About 1 million people will reach 1 0,000 degrees Fahrenheit...
in less than a second.
Mr. Secretary....
We'll just blame it on the cook.
Absolutely.
Take it north.
Roger that. Heading north.
STRANNIX: I'll take that weapon.
Quietly.
Now.
You look familiar.
I know you, don't I?
I think you do.
Been a long time.
Yes, sir. It has.
Turn around.
We'll have a tour. Step forward.
Here we have...
our Tomahawks...
speeding their way to the sunny Aloha State. Turn around.
As you can see...
there will be no return.
And I got the key.
The lock is broken. Step forward.
Sit over there.
You'll watch the end of the world on TV.
Put your feet up. Relax.
You know, you're good.
You are really good.
It's gonna be a shame to kill you.
Behold my finest work.
Do me a favor. Tell me something.
You really think blowing up a bunch of innocent people...
is gonna change anything?
What made you flip like this?
I got tired of coming up with desperate solutions...
to impossible problems created by other fucking people.
All your ridiculous, pitiful antics won't change a thing.
You and I...
we're puppets in the same sick play.
We serve the same master...
and he's an ungrateful lunatic. There's nothing we can do about it.
You and I are the same.
No. There's a difference, my man.
You have faith. I don't.
Keep the faith, Strannix.
PILOT: Locked on my nose, 1 5 miles.
Five miles, on target. Weapon status, clear.
Roger.
GARZA: Excuse me, admiral. BATES: Yes?
They intercepted one missile.
And the other one?
It slipped through.
Chief...
we've only got time for one shot. So we'll do it by the numbers.
Ryback, load the disk.
Now punch 47.
You're now on KU.
Code is six, four...
three, five...
zero, zero.
That's 643500. Is my read-back correct?
GARZA: That's affirmative.
Stand by, sir.
GARZA: Got it! Nimitz is no longer tracking.
Good man! Good man, Ryback!
Sir, call off your bombers. Call off your bombers.
We're calling off the aircraft. We're calling them off.
Thanks, Ryback. Great job! Great job!
Want to go swimming? I got a Zodiac and some C-rays...
a little umbrella....
GRANGER: I'll go with you.
She's all right! She's all right!
Good, good, all of you guys.
Great!
Good job!
Hold on in there, we'll get you out in a minute!
SAILOR: What did I miss, chief?
You'll need three or four stitches. I wanna see you down in the infirmary.
I'm afraid of needles, you know.
- What's for breakfast, Case? - Subs, Tackman. Subs!
Case, show me a move.
Here's one move.
Present arms!